## Nuno Costa

Full Name: Nuno Miguel Correia Guimarães da Costa

Sex: Male | Date of birth: 05/11/1987 | Nationality: Portuguese

**Phone:** +353830456217 | +351965227355

Email: nuno18\_9@hotmail.com | LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/nuno-costa-432024155

Address: 41 Cois Glaisin Heights, Johnstown, Navan, Co. Meath

#### About me

Excellent communication, interpersonal and Organizational skills. Positive "Can-do" attitude and willingness to learn, combined to the fact that I am highly motivated and a fast learner.

Good emotional intelligence and focus on the job.

Team player and a fan of knowledge sharing policy.

# Experience in Volunteering or Leadership

Played soccer from a young age, being team captain on several occasions in the different age groups.

Six months volunteer in the military completing recruit service.

These two experiences gave me the ability of being very organized and a good sense of team work.

## **Personal Skills**

Languages
Native Language Portuguese

#### Other Languages

#### **English**

Understanding:
Listening – C1 | Reading – C1
Speaking: Spoken interaction – C1 |
Spoken Production – C1
Writing: C1

#### **Spanish**

Understanding:
Listening – B2 | Reading – B2
Speaking: Spoken interaction – B2 |
Spoken Production – B2
Writing: A2



## **Experience**

## Training Coordinator | Covalen @Facebook - Ireland - 29/02/2020 - present

Ensures all employees receive appropriate training and retraining when processes are changed. Development and maintaining a training framework and plan for employees. Document and Report to Client of all attendance and Development plan for employees. Planning of New hire sessions and distribution of Sessions to all training team.

# Coach SME (Subject Matter Expert) | CPL/Covalen @Facebook – Ireland – 29/02/2020 – 30/08/2020

Supporting the Covalen on site policy team, Deliver Client Policy update to Community Operations analyst, Development and Implementation of various initiatives. Responsible for reporting to Operations Leads weekly performance reports and implement actions with underperforming operations analyst. Support Community operations analyst with Policy doubts and communicate with Policy team and Client in order to obtain the answer and communicating with training team on Adhoc projects and new hire support.

#### Community Operations Analyst/Auditor | CPL/Covalen @Facebook-Ireland – 04/02/2019 – 29/02/2020

Enforce the company's policies and procedures and carefully monitoring reports of abuse or explicit content on the site. Review accounts for Client and apply relevant Policies, provide market knowledge to new hire. Identify inefficiencies in workflows and suggest solutions to Coach's SME. Achieve SLA indicated by the Company and always performing above target

Coordinating with Coaches SME the scheduling and delivering of shadowing to New hire.

Safety Point of Contact for a Team of 30 reps.

Perform quality auditing for Client.

# IT Sales Manager and Helpdesk Coordinator | J. Canão, Lda - Portugal | 01/09/2018 - 26/12/2018

Development of Relationships with customers, Understand the customer business requirement and providing suitable IT solutions. Decision Making Process, develop and execute a business plan. Build a strong relationship and collaborate with partners. Outline a business plan and marketing strategies, Responsible for a Team of 10 members plus 5 customer service tech agents. Responsible of verification and approval of documentation on international and National Business according to the relevant guidelines.

Responsible for Organizing Schedules and analysing Technicians time and results. Verifying if SLA are being respected and sending satisfaction inquiries and monthly tech reports to customers and HR.





## **Professional Qualification**

01-10-2018 - Digital Marketing - IAB | Google

07/06/2017 - Canow Platform - Logistics and Shipping module - JCanão Software (Cloud Version)

23/05/2017 - BPMN - Business Process Model and Notation - Bizagi software

21/04/2017 – ERP Financials JCanão software (Cloud Version)

20/04/2017 – Technical-Commercial Training e-Sig ERP JCanão Software (Cloud version)

05/12/2016 – Training Management Level 2

19/05/2016 – Training Management Level 1

17/05/2016 – Sage L50 vs. JCanão Software e-SigEmp

13/05/2016 – Fundamentals Canow Platform – JCanão software

2012 - Gas Appliances Mechanic Course – Completed with an average score of 19,1 values in a scale of 0 to 20.

2005 - Welding Course - Completed with an average score of 17,8 values in a scale of 0 to 20.

Customer Service Tech Support | Eishtec | 20/01/2018 – 10/08/2018 Working closely with customers identifying Broadband problems and advising on the right solution.

Logging and keeping records of customer queries. Working closely with field engineers organizing customer's home visit when an additional or more serious problem is identified. Testing and identifying faulty equipment and issues related to them. Organize equipment replacements when required.

## OTC Sales Assistant | Tipp Town Pharmacy - Ireland | 12/08/2017 - 31/12/2017

Providing a professional sympathetic and supportive service to patients and identifying the right solution to meet their needs. Management and ensuring stock levels are maintained at optimal levels.

Ensure that all logistical operations are effective and efficient.

# IT Sales Manager and Helpdesk Coordinator | J. Canão, Lda - Portugal | 01/04/2015 - 11/08/2017

Development of Relationships with customers, Understand the customer business requirement and providing suitable IT solutions. Decision Making Process, develop and execute a business plan. Build a strong relationship and collaborate with partners. Outline a business plan and marketing strategies, Responsible for a Team of 10 members plus 5 customer service tech agents. Responsible of verification and approval of documentation on international and National Business according to the relevant guidelines.

Responsible for Organizing Schedules and analysing Technicians time and results. Verifying if SLA are being respected and sending satisfaction inquiries and monthly tech reports to customers and HR.

# Sales Representative and Gas Appliance Mechanic | J.J. Carvalho, Lda - Portugal | 01/01/2012 - 30/03/2015

Development of Relationships with customer, Understand the customer business requirement and providing suitable solutions.

Analyse faults in the different equipment and make budget and respective repair.

### Education

#### Code Institute | 08/2020 to Present

Full Stack Software Developer – Level 6 NFQ (Irish National Framework of Qualifications)

**High School | 2005 | Escola Secundária de Monserrate - Portugal** Art course dedicated to architecture with emphasis on mathematics and geometry.

Basic education | 2002 | Escola EB 1 do Carmo - Escola EB 2,3 Frei Bartolomeu dos Mártires – Portugal





